<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>robotics | Hitesh Kandala</title>
    <link>https://hiteshK03.github.io/tag/robotics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hiteshK03.github.io/tag/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>robotics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Hitesh Kandala</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 19:52:21 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hiteshK03.github.io/media/icon_huebd06e6b0d43802f6ac203b68475d8c7_43103_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>robotics</title>
      <link>https://hiteshK03.github.io/tag/robotics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Driving Car</title>
      <link>https://hiteshK03.github.io/project/sedrica/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 19:52:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hiteshK03.github.io/project/sedrica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was a part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.umiciitb.com/competitions/SeDriCa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Team SeDriCa&lt;/a&gt; consisting of around 20 members. We were one of the 11 finalists among 289 teams competing in the Mahindra RISE Driverless Car Challenge to build India&#39;s first self driving car targeting the level 5 autonomy and received a Mahindra E2O for development of the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&#34;sedrica.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sedrica.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Our Mahindra E2O (SeDriCa)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In my initial months, I was mainly understanding and implementing models in the computer vision subsytem, training Traffic Sign and Traffic Light classifier based on Resnet-50 and Resnet-152 architectures.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I, then switched to handle Path Planning and Decision Making subsytem as CV modules were giving decent results. I went for on-ground testing of the vehicle (in the campus) and optimized the path of the vehicle accounting for the location and information of obstacles and traffic signals using Robot Operating System (ROS).&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;One of my major contribution in this subsytem was implementing RRT* algorithm and integrating with other modules through ROS, to improve the speed and accuracy of finding path which was previously using Hybrid-A*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our self driving car intro and in news
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8lNKjX0-RKY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;sedrica_team.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sedrica_team.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our senior team members, last Christmas Eve&#39;19&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASME SDC 2019</title>
      <link>https://hiteshK03.github.io/project/asme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 19:55:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hiteshK03.github.io/project/asme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my freshmen year, I was recruited in the tech team &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.umiciitb.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Unmesh Mashruwala Innovation Cell&lt;/a&gt; along with 10 other freshmen and our first project was the competition &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.umiciitb.com/competitions/ASME&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#34;Student Design Challenge&#34;&lt;/a&gt; organised every year by American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME).
The competition required us to build a remote controlled bot of maximum dimensions 50x50, capable of picking, storing and placing balls of sizes ranging from table-tennis balls to as large as basket balls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;deepu_bot.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;deepu_bot.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our bot, which we named &#34;Deepu&#34;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learnings&#34;&gt;My Contributions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programmed Roboteq to control the encoder-geared DC motors used to rotate the mechanum wheels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programmed arduino to simultaneously control a stepper and 2 servo motors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Controlled the whole bot using transmitter during testing phase to improve speed and accuracy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code used for the competition is available 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hiteshK03/ASME-SDC-Competition&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learnings&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working hard for 3 months, we flew to Vellore for the Aisa-Pacific Regionals to compete with 20 other colleges from all over Asia. After 3 days of planning strategies and sleepless nights, we finally emerged as the Overall Winners of the Asia-Pacific Regionals. With this we qualified to represent India at the World Finals at Utah, USA in Nov 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some posts on our victory can be found
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iitb.ac.in/en/breaking-news/umic-iit-bombay-wins-asme-sdc-asia-pacific-2019#:~:text=A%20team%20of%2014%20BTech,of%20Mechanical%20Engineering%20(ASME).&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&#34;asme.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;asme.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The winning team with the judges and our bot &#34;Deepu&#34;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
