<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>network security | Hitesh Kandala</title>
    <link>https://hiteshK03.github.io/tag/network-security/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hiteshK03.github.io/tag/network-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>network security</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Hitesh Kandala</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 19:55:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hiteshK03.github.io/media/icon_huebd06e6b0d43802f6ac203b68475d8c7_43103_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>network security</title>
      <link>https://hiteshK03.github.io/tag/network-security/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intrusion Detection System</title>
      <link>https://hiteshK03.github.io/project/ids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 19:55:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hiteshK03.github.io/project/ids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project started at the time when everyone was shut in their homes, owing to the worldwide pandemic. This was done as a part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wncc-iitb.org/soc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Seasons of Code (SOC)&lt;/a&gt; organised by Web and Coding Club (WnCC), IIT Bombay. I co-ordinated in a team of 8, to build a real-time system that monitors network traffic for malicious activity. This was done with the help of raw network packet sniffer with a machine learning model detecting threats in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;IDS-OOB.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;IDS-OOB.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Block diagram of IDS.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=contribution&gt;My Contributions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My major work was related to supervising the first year students and building a machine learning model to detect threats. For this, I read many reasearch papers to find out which type of model performs best and which dataset to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We finally chose &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unb.ca/cic/datasets/ids-2017.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CICIDS2017&lt;/a&gt; dataset as this was quite recent and relevant. I then applied Pearson Correlation and Chi-square test to this dataset to select best 15 out of 81 features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I trained the chosen features with an ensemble model (consisting of classifiers such as Random-Forest, ExtraTrees, KNN, etc.) to achieve around 99% accuracy but the model was slow in making predictions and was practically not possible to use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then I trained with each of the classifiers and found that KNN and ExtraTrees gave that accuracy to the ensemble model and the delay was mainly because of KNN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally using ExtraTrees classifier, I achieved an accuracy of 99.7%, and with greatly reduced inference time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
